Alex Merecka Software Engineer / Web Developer

https://www.linkedin.com/in/alex-merecka-9814834b/ https://github.com/merecka https://merecka.github.io/ merecka@gmail.com 713.870.5307 Austin, TX based (open to relocation)

Summary

Successful & proven engineer with 15 years of engineering experience and a strong passion for software development. Experienced in managing multi-disciplined teams and large scale projects utilizing cross-functional team collaboration. Seeking opportunities to utilize my technical skills in web development along with my proven leadership abilities.

Skills

Object Oriented Programming, MVC Design, RESTful Architecture, Ruby, Ruby on Rails, Sinatra, ActiveRecord, SQL Server, JavaScript, React, Redux, HTML, CSS, Excel / Word / PowerPoint

Technical Projects

Costa Rica Surf Report App / https://github.com/merecka/my-cli-project

A Ruby based HTML scraper app that reports the daily surf conditions for multiple locations in Costa Rica.

- Coded in Ruby utilizing OOP principles
- Utilized the Nokogiri gem for scraping and parsing HTML data
- Created a menu driven Command Line Interface UI

Freelance Job Board App / https://github.com/merecka/sinatra-freelance-jobsboard-project

A job posting board app that allows users to post new jobs and apply to posted jobs.

- Coded in Ruby utilizing the Sinatra framework
- Utilized MVC structure and RESTful architecture
- Incorporated SQLite3 database with ActiveRecord ORM
- Incorporated User login security & authentication functionality using Bcrypt gem

Hostel Booking App / https://github.com/merecka/rails-wipeouthostel-website

A hotel room booking management app that allows users to make hotel room reservations and owners to manage bookings..

- Coded in Ruby utilizing the Rails framework
- Utilized MVC structure and RESTful architecture
- Incorporated SQLite3 database with ActiveRecord ORM
- Incorporated User authentication via external account credentials utilizing OmniAuth

Question & Answer Forum App / https://github.com/merecka/javascript-question-forum-project

A single page Question & Answer app which allows users to post new questions and reply to existing questions.

- HTML / CS / JavaScript front-end with a Rails API back-end
- Incorporated ES6 Class objects for OOP structuring
- Fetched and rendered data from API using AJAX and JSON
- Utilized Bootstrap for CSS styling

Work

Navigation Petroleum / Operations Manager

Experience

2017 - 2019, HOUSTON, TX

Managed the company's entire oil & gas operational activity in the Powder River Basin, WY. These areas include drilling, completion, production, & facilities engineering. Managed teams of 50+ people as well as projects in excess of \$10MM.

Chevron / Drill Site Manager & Drilling Engineer

2013 - 2016, GULF OF MEXICO

Supervised and managed the daily drilling operations on-board 6th generation drillships in the Gulf of Mexico. Managed teams of 50+ people and projects in excess of \$500MM.

Devon Energy / Petroleum Engineer

2008 - 2012, HOUSTON, TX

Performed well engineering & design, developed field operational procedures, and performed project reviews and economic analysis. Held positions of various titles including: Drilling, Completions, Production, & Reservoir Engineer.

Education

Flatiron School / Software Engineering Bootcamp

2019 - 2020

A Full-Stack Web Development training program which teaches students practical skills in modern web development & software engineering along with building web applications using in-demand programming languages.

University of Houston / Master's of Petroleum Engineering

2006 - 2008, HOUSTON, TX

Texas A&M University / Bachelor's of Science, Geology

2000 - 2004, COLLEGE STATION, TX